Guide to the James Snead Papers, 1966-1989 UA.90.F81
ULS Archives & Special Collections
James Snead Papers
1966-1989
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Snead, James A.
UA.90.F81
6.25 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains the gathered works of James A. Snead from 1966 to 1989. The collection includes his written works, both fiction and non-fiction; research; personal activities; corresepondence; and prior research done about Snead utilizing the materials in this collection. The Non-Fiction subseries encompasses his work on subjects such as Benito Cereno, James Joyce, Black Cinema, and Thomas Mann. Much of the research in the Research series pertains to these non-fiction works, but also include resources on Snead's other interests in German politics, book reviews, and general research on other writers. The Personal Acitivities series houses some of Snead's course work and lectures, as well as information from his time at Yale University. The Correspondence series contains a small amount of letters both to and from Snead. The final series holds research done on this collection of material prior to it being aquired by the University of Pittsburgh, consisting primarily of notecards.
Biography
James Arthur Snead was born in Queens, New York, in 1953. He attended Phillips Exeter Academy, graduating cum laude in 1971. After high school, Snead attended Yale, achieving Scholar of the House in Saybrook, and graduating summa cum laude in 1976 with a degree in English. At Yale, Snead's studies focused on James Joyce and Thomas Mann. For his doctorate degree, Snead attended St. John's College, Cambridge, where he graduated with a PhD in English in 1980. This doctoral work led to his 1986 book, Figures of Division: William Faulkner's Major Novels, which explored race in Faulkner's works. While in England, Snead toured around as a keyboardist with a local students' jazz band.
After graduation, Snead lived in West Germany working in finance, where he became fascinated with democracy in Germany. James, or Jamie as he was called, returned to Yale in the early 1980s as an assistant professor of English. During this time, Snead became interested in the way race was depicted in film, leading him to publish academic and popular articles on the subject. Snead, then, moved to the University of Pittsburgh in pursuit of a tenured position. Snead died unexpectedly in 1989, leaving behind many unpublished works.
After his death, Snead's estate published two books of his previously unreleased work. White Screens, Black Images: Hollywood from the Dark Side was published in 1994 and focused on his interest of the portrayal of African Americans in film. Racist Traces and Other Writings, published in 2003, was a collection of essays and fiction. Snead also left behind an unpublished major work called Visions of White, as well as many short stories and poems. In addition, Snead wrote book reviews and various articles on topics such as people of color in film, James Joyce, Thomas Mann, Greek epics, Benito Cereno, and more.
Acquisition Information
Gift of George T. Snead on December 5, 2017.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
English literature; African-American literature and culture; African American authors; Correspondence; Book reviews; Snead, James A.
- Written Works, 1972-1991; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series consists of the written works of James A. Snead, both fiction and non-fiction. His works span from 1972 to 1988. It includes both handwritten and typewritten early drafts, as well as published or circulated materials.While the Non-Fiction subseries is much larger and contains many published works, the Fiction subseries contains many handwritten, unpublished materials. Topics include, but are not limited to: People of Color in Film; German themes; Thomas Mann; and James Joyce.
  - Fiction, 1972-1991; 1.
    The Fiction subseries contains short stories, book proposals, and poetry. Most of these materials had yet to be published before Snead's death. Some materials were published posthumously by Snead's colleagues in White Screens, Black Images: Hollywood from the Dark Side and Racist Traces and Other Writings. Some of the unpublished materials lack titles and are denoted as "Unknown Draft." The majority of the works in this subseries were based around German topics, as well as issues faced by African Americans. Some notable titles from this subseries are the book Visions of White, short stories "A Matter of Peas" and "Notes of a Hybrid," and the poem "Happy for Sun Light."
    - "A Day Won" Short Story (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "A Matter of Peas" Short Story (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "A Smell of Burning Leaves: The Appearance of Oregano" Short Story (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - As a Child Draft (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Caucasian Writing (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Collection of Snead Poems, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Exploring Africa's Past" Draft (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Frankfurt Handwritten Draft (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Gute Nacht Writing (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Handwritten Draft about a Person Traveling (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Handwritten Draft on a Group of People Traveling (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Happy for Sunlight Poem (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Indecision Poem (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - James Snead Memorial Issue in Critical Quarterly, Spring 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Kent State Reflection Story Draft (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Munich Olympics Short Story (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Munich Olympics Short Story Written Draft (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Night Shades Short Story Collection (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Notes of a Hybrid/ Letters from Africa" Drafts (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Notion of Going to Oxford Autobiographical Writing Draft (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Passing" Short Story (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Possible Story Ideas (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "Two Trips Abroad" Short Story (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Unknown Draft One (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Unknown Draft Two (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Unknown Draft Three (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Unknown Draft Four (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Unknown Draft Five (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Unknown Draft Six (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Unknown Draft Seven (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Unknown Draft Eight (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Visions of White Booklet (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Visions of White Draft, January 22, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
    - Visions of White Draft (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
  - Non-Fiction, 1972-1990; 2.
    This subseries contains unpublished and published non-fiction works by James Snead. Topics for this subseries include: Thomas Mann; James Joyce; Benito Cereno; Book Reviews; William Faulkner; Greek Stories; and Race. This subseries shows the variance in subjects that facinated Snead and how his interests changed over time. A large element of his non-fiction work is his book, Figures of Division, published in 1986 on William Faulkner and his novels. Though this subseries does not contain the book, it does contain early drafts of parts of the book. Notable titles within this subseries include: "Recoding Blackness: Image and Reality in Black Independent Films;" "Misreading Race in Benito Cereno: The Silence of Babo;"and "Repitition and Realism in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg."
    - Benito Cereno
      - "Benito Cereno: Misreading Blackness" Draft (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - "Misreading Race in Benito Cereno: The Silence of Babo" Early Drafts (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - "Misreading Race in Benito Cereno: The Silence of Babo" Drafts (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - "Reading through Blackness: Colorless signifiers in Benito Cereno" in Yale Journal of Criticism, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - "The Strangeness of Babo: Delano or Benito Cereno?" Early Draft (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - "The Strangeness of Babo: Delano or Benito Cereno?" Paper Draft Version One (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - "The Strangeness of Babo: Delano or Benito Cereno?" Paper Draft Version Two (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Black Cinema, 1985-1988
      - The Birth of Black Cinema Project, Layout and Information, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Black Independent Cinema Outline, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Black Independent Film: "Britain and America" Chapter from White Screens/Black Images (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - The Coded Black: Film Stereotypes in Transition, Book Proposal (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - "Moral Primitivism in Song of the South" Draft (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - "Passion and Memory: Celebrating Blacks in Hollywood Films" Review Draft (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - "Playing the Changes: St. Clair Bournes In Motion: Amiri Baraka" Article, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - "Recoding Blackness: Image and Reality in Black Independent Films" Early Drafts (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "Recoding Blackness: Image and Reality in Black Independent Films" Drafts, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "Recoding Blackness: Image and Reality in Black Independent Films" Later Drafts (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - "Recording Blackness" Public Relations, June 18 - July 3, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - "Seeing Black: A Semiotics of Black Culture in America" Proposal, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - White Screens/Black Images Early Partial Draft (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Book Reviews, 1984-1988
      - At a Certain Age Snead Review and Notes, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Closing a Place Reviews with Notes by Snead (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Confession of a Murderer Snead review and notes, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - God Within the Shadow Book Review (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Our Conquest Snead review and Notes, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - The Price of the Ticket Snead Review, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Pigeons of Grass Book and Snead Review (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Reckless Eyeballing Snead Review and Notes (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - September Light Snead Review and Notes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Tallien Snead Review and Notes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - General Work
      - "American Fiction has not Been Itself Lately" Article Draft (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Article on Dostoevsky and his Influence on The Invisible Man (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - "Difficult Playwrights" Critique Draft (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - "Framed in their place – Paradigmatic Limitations" Article (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - "Freud's Civilization and His Discontents" Article (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - "Repetition and Literature" Abstract, June 25, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Greek
      - Bloomsbody Paper, May 21, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - "Dionysus and the Eating of God" Draft (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - "Euphemism and the Polis" Draft (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - "Necrophilia and the Garden of Adonis: Andrew Marvell and Henry James' 'Aspern Papers'" (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - "Necrophilia and the Garden of Adonis" Newer Drafts (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - James Joyce
      - Article on Character as Palimsest in Joyce (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - "The Scar of Symbolism" Drafts (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - James Joyce and Thomas Mann, 1975-1987
      - "Derkadenz, Wiederholung, Fortschritt: Ulysses and Der Zauberberg" (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Draft on Ulysses and Der Zauberberg (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - "Evasion of History in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg" Draft (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - "Mann and Joyce: On the Question of Influence" Paper, June 17, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Repetition and Realism in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg Book Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Repetition in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg Large Draft (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
      - Repetition in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg, Dissertation by Snead, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Repetition in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg Proposal, March 16, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Scholar of the House Essay on Repetition in Ulysses and Der Zauberberg, April 19, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - James Joyce and William Faulkner, July 22, 1979
      - "Hiatus and Reversal: Aspects of Repetition in Absalom, Absalom! And Ulysses" Thesis Draft Booklet, July 22, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - "Hiatus and Reversal: Aspects of Repetition in Absalom, Absalom! And Ulysses" Thesis Draft, July 22, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 49-50)
    - People of Color and Race
      - "Narration and Jack the Bear" by Snead and Ries (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - "Racist Traces in Post-modernist Theory and Literature" Drafts (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - "Repetition as a Figure of Black Culture" Article (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - "Spectatorship and Capture in King Kong: the Guilty Look" Draft (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - "White Irony: The Poles of History in A Dance of the Forest and Finnegan's Wake" Drafts (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Thomas Mann
      - Footnotes on Thomas Mann for Unknown Document (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Thomas Mann "Time is an Illusion" Draft (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - "Vision, Desire, and the Word in Thomas Mann's Tod in Venegid" Early Draft (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - "Vision, Desire, and the Word in Thomas Mann's Tod in Venegid" Draft (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - "The Vision of Desire" Clean Draft (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - "The Vision of Desire" Drafts (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - William Faulkner, 1983-1986
      - Article on Faulkner (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - As I Lay Dying (1930) Chapter Draft from Figures of Division (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Figures of Division Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Figures of Division Completed Draft, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
      - Figures of Division Draft and Bibliography, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Figures of Division Publishing Information (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Figures of Division Request Forms, July 27-August 1, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Figures of Division Second Completed Draft, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
      - Figures of Division Third Completed Draft, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - "Light in August and the Rhetorics of Racial Division" Chapter Drafts from Figures of Division, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Review Process of Figures of Division (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - "Titles of Deceit – The Rhetoric of Self and Society in Faulkner" Abstract, June 25th, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "Titles of Deceit – The Rhetoric of society in Faulkner" Handwritten Draft (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Research, 1827-1989; II.
  This series consists of research done by James A. Snead for his various non-ficion works and his own intersts. The research consists of articles and notes on Benito Cereno; books, plays, and poems; German topics; Greek topics; James Joyce; People of Color; poetry; Thomas Mann; William Faulkner; and various other writers.
  - Benito Cereno, 1.
    This subseries contains the research done on the novella Benito Cereno by Herman Melville. James Snead was paritcullary interested in racism within the novella. The research includes outlines, articles, and notes.
    - Manifesto Packet of Benito Cereno Notes (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Monkey in the Manifesto: Benito Cereno Notes on Babo (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Outlines, Points to Remember, and Notes for Cereno (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Packet of Benito Cereno Notes (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Books, Plays, and Poems, 2.
    This subseries contains research on various books, plays, and poems that were of interst to James Snead. A few of the works include: short stories by Franz Kafka; Mrs. Dalloway by Virginia Woolf; Wasteland by T.S. Eliot; and "The Cherry Orchard" play by Anton Chekhov.
    - "A Report to an Academy" Short Story by Franz Kafka Research (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "A Week on the Oncord and Merrimack Rivers" by William Drake (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Abortion Book Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "The Cherry Orchard" Play by Anton Chekhov Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Figures of Transcendence in Romantic Poetry Research, December 9, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "In the Penal Colony" Short Story by Franz Kafka (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy novel by Laurence Stern Notes (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Literature to Film Notes (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Moby Dick Notes and Research (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. Dalloway Novel by Virginia Woolf Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "My Monster/My Self" Article on Frankenstein, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Robinson Crusoe Notes (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Sir Giwain" Poem by Anonymous Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Volpone" Play by Ben Jonson Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Wasteland by T.S. Eliot Notes (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - General, 1975-1988; 3.
    This subseries overviews general research done by James Snead that does not fit in other categories, including research on art museums, Freud, and possible paper topics.
    - Art Museum Research (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - British Monarch Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Caribbean English Writers List, May 1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Ceremonial Actions Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Death as Possibility Research, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Dissertation on Giryama by Unknown (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Freud Research (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Grammar and Writing Research, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Media Matter Research, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Montaigne Publications Research, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Possible Paper Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Research Notes (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Selections from "The Ash Keeper's Everlasting Passion Week" by Louis Daniel Brodsky, May 22, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Self-Reflected Research (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Snead's Notes on Learning French (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Technology Research, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Why is there Salt in the Sea? By Brigite Schwaiger (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Yale Review Journal with Note to Snead Concerning Book Reviews, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - German, 1827-1979; 4.
    This subseries covers research done by James Snead on Biermann, music, posters, and various articles. The majority of the research is done in the German.
    - Biermann Research, 1966-1977 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Buch der Lieder (Book of songs), 1827 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Catalog for German-English Studies Books (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Emerson and Thoreau Research (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "Freedom of Opinion, Freedom of Travel" for Wolf Biermann event at Ruhr-University in Bochum, Germany, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - German Music Research (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Information on Kunsthaus Zürich Collection, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Thomas Pynchon Article Research (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Greek, 5.
    This subseries contains research done by James Snead on Greek works and mythology.
    - Greece's Religion of Art Research (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Greek Epic Research Notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mythology Notes and Newspaper Clippings (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Orpheus Research (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ovid, Acis, Galatea, and Polyphemus, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - James Joyce, 6.
    This subseries overviews the research done by James Snead on James Joyce and his writings. The research includes general notes and articles,which were most likely used for the Snead's graduate dissertation on Thomas Mann and James Joyce.
    - James Joyce Research, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Room of Infinite Possibilities, History, Hegel, and Joyce Articles, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Some Perfactory Romances on Character in Joyce (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Ulysses Appendix (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Ulysses Indexes by Schutte (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - People of Color, 1973-1989; 7.
    This subseries contains the various research of James Snead regarding African Americans and other people of color. Topics include, but are not limited to: Beauty and Fashion, College, Museums, Sports, Film, War, and Racism. This research was conducted later in Snead's life, from 1973 to 1988.
    - Art Research, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Beauty and Fashion Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Blackness without Blood" by Henry Louis Gates, Jr., 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - College Research, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dance Research, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Economics Research, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Education Research, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Film Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Government Research, 1973-1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Harlem for Passing Research Notes (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Joseph Himes and Industry Article (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Joseph Himes Interview (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Literature Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Research, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Museums Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Music Research, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Nanny Business Research, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - New York City Real Estate Research, November 17, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Racism Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Research, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Sports Research, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Television Research, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - War Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - White Supremacy Research, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Poetry, 1976-1980; 8.
    This subseries contains poetry research done by James Snead, including a booklet of poems from Saybrook College in which Snead attended, as well as poetic knowledge papers.
    - Poems sponsored by Saybrook College, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Poetic Knowledge Papers, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Thomas Mann, 9.
    This subseries contains James Snead's research on Thomas Mann, which was most likely used for his graduate dissertation on Thomas Mann and James Joyce.
    - The Magic Mountain Appendix (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Thomas Mann Research, 1927-1982 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
  - William Faulkner, 1970-1986; 10.
    This subseries is a collection of James Snead's research on William Faulkner, which was most likely used in part during the writing of Snead's book, Figures of Division.
    - Absalom Absalom! Notes, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Faulkner Research and Notes, 1970-1986 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Writers, 1948-1984; 11.
    This subseries is made up of research on various writers, including Andre Gide, Dante Alighieri, Ralph Waldo Emerson, Herman Lenz, Jaques Lacan, Marcel Proust, Sherman Paul, and others. The research consists of written notes and articles about the writers.
    - André Gide Research, 1948-1968 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Authors in New England Research (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Dante Alighieri Research Notes (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Emerson's Tragic Sense by Whicher Research (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Hermann Lenz Research, 1973-1984 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Jaques Lacan Notes (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Johnathan Swift Research Notes (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Marcel Proust Research, 1950-1971 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Sherman Paul Research (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Wordsworth: The History in Imagination by Alan Liu (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Personal Activities, 1967-1990; III.
  This series contains classwork, lectures, public speeches, course books, and music created by Snead, primarily documenting his work as an academic.
  - "The Black Atlantic Visual Tradition" Class Information, Spring 1983 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - "Blacks in America Cinema: A Historical Survey" with Snead as Panelist (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - "Blacks in Media" Lecture (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Class Notes and Outlines for Classes, 1980 - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - The Color Purple Classwork, February 1986 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1967 – 1986 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - "Death in Venice" Lecture Outline, October 7th, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Duel Speech (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - "Emerson, Thoreau, Melville: Wilderness Within and Without" Lecture (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - English 50w Critical Reading Course Book (Box 4, Folder 64-65)
  - English 50 (UHC) Critical Reading and Writing Course Book (Box 4, Folder 66)